<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TourGuide</string>

    <!--Pharaonic Strings-->
    <string name="pyramids_name">Pyramids of Giza</string>
    <string name="pyramids_description">This complex of ancient monuments includes the three pyramid complexes known as the Great Pyramids,
        the massive sculpture known as the Great Sphinx, several cemeteries,
        a workers\' village and an industrial complex.
        It is located in the Western Desert,
        approximately 9 km  west of the Nile river at the old town of Giza, and about 13 km
        southwest of Cairo city centre.</string>

    <string name="pyramid_of_djoser_name">Pyramid of Djoser</string>
    <string name="pyramid_of_djoser_description">is an archeological remain in the Saqqara necropolis, Egypt,
        northwest of the city of Memphis. It was built ca. 27th century BC during the Third dynasty
        for the burial of Pharaoh Djoser by his vizier, Imhotep. The pyramid is the central
        feature of a vast mortuary complex in an enormous courtyard surrounded by ceremonial structures and decoration.</string>

    <string name="sphinx_name">Sphinx</string>
    <string name="sphinx_description">A sphinx is a mythical creature with the head of a human and the body of a lion.</string>

    <string name="abu_simbel_name">Abu Simbel Temple</string>
    <string name="abu_simbel_description">village in Nubia, southern Egypt,
        near the border with Sudan. They are situated on the western bank of Lake Nasser,
        about 230 km southwest of Aswan (about 300 km by road).
        The complex is part of the UNESCO World Heritage Site known as the
        "Nubian Monuments" which run from Abu Simbel downriver to Philae (near Aswan).
        The twin temples were originally carved out of the mountainside in the 13th century BC
        , during the 19th dynasty reign of the Pharaoh Ramesses II.
        They serve as a lasting monument to the king and his queen Nefertari,
        and commemorate his victory at the Battle of Kadesh. Their huge external rock relief figures have become iconic</string>

    <string name="valley_of_the_kings_name">Valley of the Kings</string>
    <string name="valley_of_the_kings_description">is a valley in Egypt where, for a period of nearly 500 years from the 16th to 11th century BC
        , rock cut tombs were excavated for the Pharaohs and powerful nobles of the New Kingdom</string>

    <!--Religious Strings-->
    <string name="mount_sinai_name">Mount Sinai</string>
    <string name="mount_sinai_description">Mount Horeb or Gabal Musa,
        is a mountain in the Sinai Peninsula of Egypt that is a possible location of the biblical Mount Sinai
        , which is considered a holy site by the Abrahamic religions. Mount Sinai is mentioned many times
        in the Book of Exodus and other books of the Bible, and the Quran. According to Jewish,
        Christian, and Islamic tradition, the biblical Mount Sinai was the place where Moses received the Ten Commandments.</string>

    <string name="hanging_church">The Hanging Church</string>
    <string name="hanging_church_description">also known as the Hanging Church  is one of the oldest churches in Egypt and
        the history of a church on this site dates to the 3rd century AD</string>

    <string name="azhar_mosque_name">Al-Azhar Mosque</string>
    <string name="azhar_mosque_description">is an Egyptian mosque in Islamic Cairo. Al-Mu\'izz li-Din Allah of the Fatimid dynasty
        commissioned its construction for the newly established capital city in 970.
        Its name is usually thought to allude to the Islamic prophet Muhammad\'s daughter Fatimah,
        a revered figure in Islam who was given the title az-Zahrā
        It was the first mosque established in Cairo, a city that has since gained the nickname
        "the City of a Thousand Minarets</string>

    <string name="saint_catherine_name">Saint Catherine Monastery</string>
    <string name="saint_catherine_description">Built between 548 and 565, the monastery is one of the oldest working Christian monasteries in the world
        . The site contains the world\'s oldest continually operating library,
        possessing many unique books including the Syriac Sinaiticus and, until 1859,
        the Codex Sinaiticus. A small town with hotels and swimming pools, called Saint Katherine City,
        has grown around the monastery.</string>

    <!--Modern Strings-->
    <string name="bibliotheca_alex_name">Bibliotheca Alexandrina</string>
    <string name="bibliotheca_alex_description"> is a major library and cultural center located on the shore of the Mediterranean
        Sea in the Egyptian city of Alexandria. It is both a commemoration of the
        Library of Alexandria that was lost in antiquity, and an attempt to
        rekindle something of the brilliance that this earlier center of study and erudition represented.</string>

    <string name="egyptian_museum_name">Egyptian Museum</string>
    <string name="egyptian_museum_description">known commonly as the Egyptian Museum or Museum of Cairo,
        in Cairo, Egypt, is home to an extensive collection of ancient Egyptian antiquities
        . It has 120,000 items, with a representative amount on display, the remainder
        in storerooms. The edifice is one of the largest museums in the region. As of July 2017, the museum is open to the public.</string>

    <string name="cairo_tower_name">Cairo Tower</string>
    <string name="cairo_tower_description">is a free-standing concrete tower located in Cairo, Egypt
        . At 187 m (614 ft), it has been the tallest structure
        in Egypt and North Africa for about 50 years. It was the
        tallest structure in Africa for 10 years, until 1971 when
        it was surpassed by Hillbrow Tower in South Africa</string>

    <string name="luxor_museum_name">Luxor Museum</string>
    <string name="luxor_museum_description">The Luxor Museum was inaugurated in 1975
        . It is a two-story buildingThe range of artifacts on display
        is far more restricted than the country\'s main collections
        in the Museum of Antiquities in Cairo; this was, however,
        deliberate, since the museum prides itself on the quality of
        the pieces it has, the uncluttered way in which they are
        displayed, and the clear multilingual labeling used</string>

    <!--Other Strings-->
    <string name="ras_muhammad_np_name">Ras Muhammad National Park</string>
    <string name="ras_muhammad_np_description">is a national park in Egypt at the southern extreme of
        the Sinai Peninsula, overlooking the Gulf of Suez on the
        west and the Gulf of Aqaba to the east.</string>

    <string name="khan_el_khalili_name">Khan el-Khalili</string>
    <string name="khan_el_khalili_description"> is a major souk in the historic center of Islamic Cairo.
        The bazaar district is one of Cairo's main attractions for tourists and Egyptians alike. </string>

    <string name="saladin_citadel_name">Saladin Citadel</string>
    <string name="saladin_citadel_description">is a medieval Islamic fortification in Cairo
        , Egypt. The location, on Mokattam hill near the center of Cairo, was
        once famous for its fresh breeze and grand views of the city. It is
        now a preserved historic site, with mosques and museums. In 1976,
        it was proclaimed by UNESCO as a part of the World Heritage Site
        Historic Cairo (Islamic Cairo) which was "the new centre of the
        Islamic world, reaching its golden age in the 14th century</string>

    <string name="qaitbay_name">Citadel of Qaitbay</string>
    <string name="qaitbay_description">Tis a
        15th-century defensive fortress located on the Mediterranean
        sea coast, in Alexandria, Egypt. It was established in 1477 AD
        (882 AH) by Sultan Al-Ashraf Sayf al-Din Qa'it Bay. The Citadel
        is situated on the eastern side of the northern tip of Pharos
        Island at the mouth of the Eastern Harbour</string>
</resources>
